Register of the Alfred M. Lilienthal papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- TAPES, 1954-1991 (Box Vault)
  - a) Speech, "Where Goes the Middle East?" Windsor Hotel, Montreal, Canada, (meeting disturbed by Maronites), 5/15/81; C (Item 143, Item (601))
  - a&b) Baghdad interview with editor Simawi of Al Baaf Magazine, 7/9/84; C (Item 144, Item (602))
  - a) CBC after Israel's invasion of Lebanon, 9/82; C (Item 145, Item (603))
  - a) Mid 70's, comments on Israeli pressure in Washington, D.C. on Capitol Hill - Scott vs. Percy, and leakage to Israel re Hawk sale to Jordan through Case and Bingham Zionist assistants, C (Item 146, Item (604))
  - a) Debate with Martin Abend, Metromedia TV, 5/31-6/1/74; C (Item 147, Item (703))
  - a) Phone interview with Tass, 5/13/80; C (Item 148, Item (705))
  - b) Speech, Dutch Treat Club, New York City,; Harry Steiger, 3/17/81
  - a&b) Phone interview by Terry Gross, WHYY, Philadelphia, PA, 3/18/83; C (Item 149, Item (706))
  - a&b) Ad, C (Item 150, Item (707))
  - a) Appearance on TV Forum, Ch.6, San Juan, Puerto Rico, (with an introduction by Mrs. Santiago), 3/30/83; C (Item 151, Item (750))
  - b) Speech, University of Puerto Rico, San Juan, 3/31/83
  - a&b) Doug Carrick's show, WAVI, Dayton, OH, 12/16/81; C (Item 152, Item (751))
  - a) Dictation re Henry Kissinger, 1/77; C (Item 153, Item (752))
  - a&b) Grand Junction, CO; phone add-on from Phoenix, KREX Radio, 2/4/83; C (Item 154, Item (753))
  - a) "Chez Ottawa," FM, 5/25/82; C (Item 155, Item (754))
  - a) Discussion with Mohamed Mehdi on AP to AP (Arab People to American People) TV, New York City, (aired 4/22, 4/24, and in May), 4/16/82; C (Item 156, Item (755))
  - a&b) Dictation in Palestinian camp re Wachs, C (Item 157, Item (757))
  - a&b) Call-in show, WTAR, Norfolk, VA, 4/27/82; C (Item 158, Item (758))
  - a&b) Coverage of AWACS sale, News Center 4, WNBC TV, 10/28/81; C (Item 159, Item (759))
  - a) "Inquiry," CFPL TV, London, Ontario, 3/21/86; C (Item 160, Item (760))
  - a&b) Interview by Bob Grant, WMCA Radio, New York City, 12/15/80; C (Item 161, Item (762))
  - a) Menachem Begin on "Meet the Press,", 1977; C (Item 162, Item (764))
  - a) Interview by Janet Langhart, WMCA Radio, New York City, 4/2/80; C (Item 163, Item (765))
  - b) Khaled Fahoum, former chairman of the Palestinian National Committee, in Damascus, Syria; and assorted conversations at Israeli Airport with soldiers en route to West Bank
  - a) Phone calls after ad appears in the New York Times, C (Item 164, Item (767))
  - a) Speech, "Middle East Terror," McGill University, Montreal, Canada, 3/26/86; C (Item 165, Item (768))
  - a) Speech, "Where Goes the Middle East?" Dumbarton Town Hall, N.H., at Captive Nations Day Ceremony, 7/19/80; C (Item 166, Item (769))
  - a&b) Interview for "Middle East in Focus," KPFK Radio, Los Angeles, CA, 12/8/82; C (Item 167, Item (770))
  - a) "Newsmakers," WTMJ TV, Milwaukee, WI, 6/24/82; C (Item 168, Item (771))
  - a) Appearance on "Day by Day," hosted by Andy Rapp, Ch.19, Delta College, University City, MI, 5/18/82; C (Item 169, Item (772))
  - a) Speech, Monterey Institute of International Studies, CA, 2/14/1983; C (Item 170, Item (773))
  - a) Interview by Pia Lindstrom re Iraq-Iran War on "Live at Five," NBC, New York City, 9/23/80; C (Item 171, Item (801))
  - a) Answer to AML by R. P. Lochman of Detroit on "Day by Day," Ch.19, Delta College, University City, MI, 5/18/82; C (Item 172, Item (802))
  - a) Speech, Princeton University, PA, 3/10/82; C (Item 173, Item (803))
  - b) AML and two young lawyers on Ch.10, St. Thomas, Virgin Islands
  - a&b) Speech, UC Berkeley, CA, 2/15/83; C (Item 174, Item (804))
  - a&b) Interview by Janet Reid on "People Talk," KDKA, Pittsburgh, PA, 10/19/81; C (Item 175, Item (805))
  - a) Interview by Rob Michaels on "Open Line," WBSM, 9/8/82; C (Item 176, Item (807))
  - b) AWB and Al Green
  - a) Speech, "How the Palestinians Can Win," An-Najah University, Nablus, 12/7/81; C (Item 177, Item (808))
  - b) Translation of speech, and question and answer period
  - a) KOY TV, Phoenix, AZ, 2/2/83; C (Item 178, Item (809))
  - b) Questions
  - a&b) Speech, University of Arizona State, Phoenix, AZ, 2/3/83; C (Item 179, Item (810))
  - a) Press conference, University of Arizona, Tucson, (filmed by WGON TV; Tucson TV used part of it that evening), 2/9/83; C (Item 180, Item (811))
  - b) Interview by Bert Sass, News Center 9, ABC; Carol Karsch, Tucson JCC secretary
  - a&b) Interview by J. Watson, WYIS, Phoenixville, PA, and call-in, 12/19/81; C (Item 181, Item (812))
  - a) Interview by Prof. Dwight Simpson at San Francisco State University,; KQED, San Francisco, CA, 2/20/83; C (Item 182, Item (813))
  - a) Michael Anthony Hoffman II's comment on Zionism and Racism, and the Beirut massacres (leading to his dismissal from Ithaca radio station), 1982; C (Item 183, Item (814))
  - a&b) Bill Smith's program, WIOD, Miami, FL, 1/13/82; C (Item 184, Item (815))
  - Continuation of Tape 184, C (Item 185, Item (816))
  - a&b) Speech, Glasgow University, Scotland, UK, 11/18/81; C (Item 186, Item (817))
  - a) Phone interview from Mobile, AL, for "Open Line" with Christina Bowers, WKRG, New York City, 6/3/83; C (Item 187, Item (818))
  - a) Speech and question and answer period, New York City, 5/31/79; C (Item 188, Item (819))
  - b) End of question and answer period
  - a&b) "Rapline," WKPA, Pennsylvania, 7/6/82; C (Item 189, Item (820))
  - a&b) Speech, Stetson University, Deland, FL, 1/6/82; C (Item 190, Item (821))
  - a) Phone interview, WINZ, Miami, 12/82; C (Item 191, Item (821))
  - a) Speech, Dade Community College, Miami, FL, 1/12/82; C (Item 192, Item (822))
  - a&b) WSTV Radio, Steubenville, OH, 1/25/82; C (Item 193, Item (823))
  - a) Prince Saud on "Issues and Answers," ABC TV, 5/29/77; C (Item 194, Item (900))
  - b) Middle East
  - a) Speech, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J., 4/29/82; C (Item 195, Item (901))
  - a) Appearance on Mike Seigel's talk show, WGBS, Miami, FL, 2/22/83; C (Item 196, Item (42))
  - a) CBC Sunday Morning re the Middle East, 7/25/82; C (Item 197, Item (52))
  - a) Speech, "Roots of the Middle East Conflict" (Part II), University of Ottawa, 3/24/86; C (Item 198, Item (3))
  - a) Prof. Geo Lenczkowski and AML at Libyan Youth Conference, Tripoli, Libya, 5/16/73; C (Item 199, Item (64))
  - a) Dictation from Bahrain, 6/5/80; C (Item 200, Item (/))
  - a) Branden-Buchanan show, WRC, (phone-in from Washington, D.C. to Tucson, AZ), 2/9/83; C (Item 201, Item (1))
  - a) Terry Gross program, WHYY, Philadelphia, PA, 3/8/83; C (Item 202, Item (2))
  - a) Interview with call-in questions, "Talk of Houston," KPRH Radio, Houston, TX, 9/30/83; C (Item 203, Item (3))
  - a) Speech, 14th American Atheists Convention, Lexington, KY, 4/21/84; C (Item 204, Item (4))
  - b) Speech, "Zionism, the Occupying Power," IPO Conference, Vienna, Austria, 5/13/84
  - a) Interview of Samawi, editor of Al-Baaf Magazine, Baghdad, Iraq; Arab chanting, 7/84; C (Item 205, Item (5))
  - a) Conversation/interview of Samawi, 7/9/84; C (Item 206, Item (6))
  - a) YMCA Jerusalem: Beit Sahour speech, 7/19/84; C (Item 207, Item (7))
  - a) Interview in Cairo, Egypt (later used on Cairo Radio), 7/31/84; C (Item 208, Item (8))
  - a) Remarks, Sabra & Shatila Memorial, Washington, D.C., (includes Clovis Maksoud's remarks), 9/15/84; C (Item 209, Item (9))
  - a) Remarks, Sabra & Shatila Memorial, Arab American groups, Washington, D.C., 9/15/84; C (Item 210, Item (10))
  - a) Part of interview, WORT Radio, Madison, WI, 12/7/84; C (Item 211, Item (12))
  - b) Part of press conference on 2nd visit to Prag, Czechoslovakia, 5/28/85
  - a) Interview by Abdul Salem Y. Massarueh for Arab newspapers at Foundry Restaurant, 3/10/85; C (Item 212, Item (13))
  - a) Speech, Organization of Arab Students, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., 5/2/85; C (Item 213, Item (14))
  - a) NAAA Convention - Authors' Roundtable, 5/5/85; C (Item 214, Item (15))
  - a) Dictation for lectures at University of London, UK, and at Institute on Strategic Studies, +13/85, 5/10; C (Item 215, Item (16))
  - b) In discussion at Institute on Strategic Studies, 5/13/85
  - a) Speech, "Wanted: A New Middle East Policy," Freedoms Foundation, Valley Forge, PA, 6/4/85; C (Item 216, Item (17))
  - Same as Tape 216, C (Item 217, Item (18))
  - Same as Tape 216, C (Item 218, Item (19))
  - Master copy of Tape 216, C (Item 219, Item (20))
  - a) Speech, Cornell Club of Washington luncheon, Washington, D.C., 9/10/85; C (Item 220, Item (23))
  - a) Interview by John McCullouch on his call-in show, WWWE Radio, Cleveland, OH, (9:30-10:00), 10/14/85; C (Item 221, Item (24))
  - a) Continuation of Tape 221 (10:00 - l0: 30-11:00), 30 and 10:; C (Item 222, Item (25))
  - a) Dictation of letter to the New York Times on the Achille Lauro highjacking, 10/14/85; C (Item 223, Item (27))
  - a) Interview by Steve Dion, WGUN TV, Tucson, AZ, 11/25/85; C (Item 224, Item (28))
  - a) "Crossfire" with Tom Braden, Congressman Dornan, and David Bar-Ilan, CNN, 12/5/85; C (Item 225, Item (29))
  - a&b) Debate between Hyman Bookbinder (ADL) and Said Areikat (Palestinian Congress of North America) re Israel's raid on Iraq on John Cigna's show, KDKA Radio, Pittsburgh, PA, (AML was cancelled out of the show, but was interviewed two days later after protesting), 6/17/81; C (Item 226, Item (166))
  - a) Mark Schreiber, KQV, Pittsburgh, PA, (sabotage SS), Fall 1980; C (Item 227, Item (/))
  - a) Debate with Hal Saunders and Wolf Blitzer re the Middle East Conflict on BIZNET "Ask Washington," U.S. Chamber of Commerce, (studio copy), 12/10/85; C (Item 228, Item (30))
  - aML's recording of Tape 228, C (Item 229, Item (31))
  - Interview by Merle Pollis, Radio 11, WWWE Cleveland, 1/7/86; C (Item 230, Item (33))
  - Continuation of Tape 230, C (Item 231, Item (33))
  - aML re Libya, 5/8/86; C (Item 232, Item (36))
  - a) Interview by Charles Metropolis, Radio Jordan, 7/20/84; R (Item 233, Item (7A))
  - Interview from Athens, Greece, of recent deportees; background on Al-Awdah ship, 2/11 or 12/88; C (Item 234, Item (407))
  - Comments from Jerusalem on the Intifadah, 2/15/88; C (Item 235, Item (408))
  - Further comments from Jerusalem on Soviet Jewry, universalism, the Holocaust, and Elie Wiesel, 2/88; C (Item 236, Item (409))
  - aML in Gaza: interview of Abu-Rahmed; visit to Mrs. Nassar's home; hospital; reception at National Hotel, 2/88; C (Item 237, Item (400))
  - Continuation of reception at National Hotel for Socialist International Union reception, 2/23/88; C (Item 238, Item (401))
  - Press conference at PLO Office in Tunis, Tunisia, 3/6/88; C (Item 239, Item (402))
  - Continuation of press conference, C (Item 240, Item (403))
  - a) Conversation with Hassan Ahmed Khalil and family at Jalazone refugee camp, 2/21/88; C (Item 241, Item (405))
  - b) Ecumenical service and other events at Athens; Al-Awdah ship happening
  - a) Continuation of Tape 241; report on the arrival of George Shultz in Jerusalem on the day of the attack on AML at Ramallah and struggle over tear gas canister, 2/26/88; C (Item 242, Item (406))
  - b) Beginning of Tape 241 (talk with Palestinian family at Jalazone)
  - Talk with Sullivan, Ch.5, WNBC Radio?, ?; threat on AML's life; Jeffrey Kolbrook, Rabbi Rappoport, Wellborn, 4/11/65; C (Item 243, Item (/))
  - Dictation from Bahrain, 6/5/80; C (Item 244, Item (7II))
  - a) Debate with Bob Grant on "Newsmaker,", 11/4/74; C (Item 245, Item (100))
  - b) Nobile (1st tape): heated conversation over media distortions
  - a) Speech, "Where Goes the Middle East?" Princeton University, PA, 3/10/82; C (Item 246, Item (/))
  - a) Call from anonymous protester re ad in the New York Times [up to 232], C (Item 247, Item (/))
  - News of the Israeli invasion of Lebanon [starts at 465]; AML on Counterpoint, Station CF, Montreal,; undetermined conversation, 6/7/82; C (Item 248, Item (/))
  - Dictation re Saudi psychosis following luncheon for AML at the Equestrian Club, and refusal of young Saudi leaders to participate in anti-Zionism campaign, 6/80; C (Item 249, Item (/))
  - a) Phone conversations with various people at WABC re AML's demand for equal time on "Accent On," in particular with Douglas Land, attorney for WABC, re obligation to present both sides, C (Item 250, Item (/))
  - b) Conversations with Skinner and Warren Richardson re the press
  - Press conference, National Press Club, Washington, D.C., 8/31/78; C (Item 251, Item (/))
  - Speech, "Roots of the Middle East Conflict" (Part I), University of Ottawa, 3/24/86; C (Item 252, Item (/))
  - Libyan memorial service and press conference sponsored by the USA Holy Land State Committee, c., Spring 1986; C (Item 253, Item (/))
  - Speech and most of the question and answer period, Phi Beta Kappa Association, Washington, D.C., 10/16/85; C (Item 254, Item (/))
  - Question and answer period, University of Western Ontario, London, Canada, 3/21/86; C (Item 255, Item (/))
  - Phone interview, KPFK Los Angeles, with Pacifica upon return from Palestine National Council meeting in Algiers, 12/1/88; C (Item 256, Item (/))
  - Dialogue with Quebec Jewish community leader Stephen Lipper, Rick Moffat Show, CJAD Radio, Montreal, Canada, 3/22/88; C (Item 257, Item (/))
  - a) Speech, "What Price Middle East Peace?" George Washington University, Washington, D.C., 1/26/88; C (Item 258, Item (/))
  - Interview, "A.M." LBC Radio, London, Great Britain, 11/22/88, re significance of Algiers conference and statement by the Palestine National Council, C (Item 259, Item (/))
  - Interview with call-in questions, "Talk of Houston," KPRH, Houston, Texas, 9/30/83; C (Item 260, Item (/))
  - a&b) Miscellaneous dictation with media and personalities at time of Unitarian Church speech, October 1980-1981; C (Item 261, Item ( A ))
  - a) Call for Middle East dialogue [from only], 40 to 79; C (Item 262, Item ( B ))
  - appearance on Radio Baghdad, Iraq, 3/24/65; R (Item 263, Item (RR1))
  - 7th Annual Asian Institute, Northwest Nazarene College, Nampa, Idaho, 1/8/70; R (Item 264, Item (RR2))
  - Interview by Bob Grant, WMCA, New York City, 2/72 (day after ad in New York Times), R (Item 265, Item (RR3))
  - appearance on Radio Kuwait, 1974; R (Item 266, Item (RR5))
  - appearance on Barry Farber's show, WOR, New York City, 1966; R (Item 267, Item (RR6))
  - Rebuttal to Jim Branch's commentary of on WRFM, New York City, 12/17/71, 12/2; R (Item 268, Item (RR7))
  - Ceremony by children at Palestinian Red Crescent, Tripoli, Libya, 5/73; R (Item 269, Item (RR8))
  - appearance on Barry Gray's show, WMCA, New York City, 5/15/57; R (Item 270, Item (RR9))
  - Appearance on "The World Tonight," BBC, London, UK, (after Ma'alot and meeting Abu Nidal). This appears to be part II, 5/16/74; R (Item 271, Item (RR10))
  - Interview on Radio Jordan, Amman, 1954; R (Item 272, Item (RR11))
  - Speech, Unitarian Church, Nantucket, MA, ("War Comes to Nantucket"). Question and answer period only, 7/71; R (Item 273, Item (RR12))
  - Speech, Los Angeles Breakfast Club, CA, 4/4/56; R (Item 274, Item (RR13))
  - Appearance on Radio Baghdad, Iraq, 6/65 (or 63); R (Item 276, Item (RR14))
  - a&b) Speech, "Middle East: Friend or Foe?" Marine Memorial Building, San Francisco, CA, 4/9/56; R (Item 276, Item (RR15))
  - Debate with Martin Abend re ad in the Wall Street Journal, Metromedia TV, Ch.5, New York City, Fall 1974; R (Item 277, Item (RR16))
  - Devotional address, Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah, 10/15/70; R (Item 278, Item (RR17))
  - Debate with Martin Abend, Metromedia TV, Ch.5, 2/7/74; R (Item 279, Item (RR18))
  - Appearance on "Night Beat," WNBC Radio, with host John Nebel, Kevin O'Dougherty, Mr. Karash, and Rabbi Silver, 6/11/57; R (Item 280, Item (RR19))
  - Debate with Rabbi Silver re Arab Boycott on John Nebel's show, WNBC Radio, 4/11/65; R (Item 281, Item (RR20))
  - Continuation of Tape 281, R (Item 282, Item (RR21))
  - Speech, Middle East Center, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT, 2/26/68; R (Item 283, Item (RR22))
  - Speech, "A Jew Looks at Zionism: The Other Side of the Middle East Coin," SUNY, Albany, NY, 4/28/69; R (Item 284, Item (RR23))
  - Speech, Youth Conference, Tripoli, Libya, (25th anniversary of Israel), 5/15/73; R (Item 285, Item (RR24))
  - Appearance, Radio Damascus, Syria, (at time when substitued for Yasir Arafat to give a speech on "Palestine Day," May 15), 5/75; R (Item 286, Item (RR25))
  - Interview on "Headliner," WMAL TV, Washington, D.C., 3/10/74; R (Item 287, Item (/))
  - a) Speech, "Where Goes the Middle East?" Student Center, University of Houston, TX, 11/30/67; R (Item 288, Item (/))
  - b) Apperance with Reverend Anis Shorosh on "Anything Goes," KTRH, Houston, TX, 11/30/67
  - Speech, "Arabs, Israelis, Oil, and Trouble," Rotary Club, Nantucket, MA, 7/17/63; R (Item 289, Item (/))
  - Radio interview on Libyan Broadcasting Service, Tripoli, Libya, 4/25/70; R (Item 290, Item (/))
  - Press Conference, Windsor, Ontario, Canada, 1/26/69; R (Item 291, Item (/))
  - Debate with Sidney Zion and call-in period on "Advise and Dissent: The Community Response to McNeil-Lehrer," New York City TV, c. 1978; R (Item 292, Item (/))
  - Prague, Czechoslovakia, (or December 1988) [bad quality], 5/28/85; V (Item 293, Item (1))
  - Press conference, Prague, Czechoslovakia, 5/29/85; R (Item 294, Item (2))
  - appearance on Arab-American radio program, Tom Shire and Linda Simon, 3 callers, 6/22/85; C (Item 295, Item (3))
  - Speech, Lebanese Syrian Canadian Association, Montreal, Canada, 3/25/86; C (Item 296, Item (4A))
  - Same as Tape 296, C (Item 297, Item (4B))
  - Memorial service for the victims in Lybia, Washington Hotel, and press conference organized by the Holy Land State Committee (HLSC), with AML and others speaking, 4/22/86; C (Item 298, Item (5))
  - W. W. Baker on "Bob Grant Show," WABC-770 AM, 9/19/86; C (Item 299, Item (6))
  - Comments, Forum on Terrorism, 1987 Student Symposium on International Terrorism, Millsaps College, Jackson, Mississippi, 1/20-21/87; C (Item 300, Item (7A))
  - Continuation of Tape 300, C (Item 301, Item (7B))
  - Speech, "What Price Middle East Peace?" George Washington University, Washington, D.C., 1/26/88; C (Item 302, Item (8))
  - Operation "Shining Sun," a major offensive of the National Liberation Army of Iran, (may include AML's commentary), 3/28/88; V (Item 303, Item (9))
  - Phone interview by Judith Gabriel of Pacifica Radio, CA, 7/10/88; C (Item 304, Item (10))
  - a) Speech, San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA, 3/28/89; C (Item 305, Item (11))
  - b) Question and answer period
  - aDC National Convention, Washington, D.C., XII: "Eyewitness Israel" (includes AML's comments), 4/13-16/89.; V (Item 306, Item (12A))
  - Continuation of Tape 306: Saturday Awards Banquet, V (Item 307, Item (12B))
  - Speech and post-address conversations, Rotary Club of Washington, D.C., 6/14/89; C (Item 308, Item (13))
  - Meir Kahane's speech followed by question and answer period, National Press Club, Washington, D.C., C (Item 309, Item (14))
  - aML meeting with Mr. Shen and Mr. Zhand from China, c., spring 1988; C (Item 310, Item (15))
  - Interview by Bob Dalton and call-in on "For Your Information," WTOP, Washington, D.C., re The Other Side of the Coin, 1/19/66; R (Item 311, Item (/))
  - Middle East Voices, 1958; R (Item 312, Item (/))
  - Same as Tape 312 [not as good a recording], R (Item 313, Item (/))
  - "Empathy," WWDC, Washington, D.C., 2/3/76; R (Item 314, Item (/))
  - Continuation of Tape 314, R (Item 315, Item (/))
  - Press conference at Republican National Convention, San Francisco, (question of nationalization of Suez Canal), 1956; R (Item 316, Item (/))
  - "Middle East Crisis" on Face to Face, CBS, Salt Lake City, Utah, 10/28/73; R (Item 317, Item (/))
  - Panel discussion on Brad Crandell's show, NBC, followed by a telephone poll, - AML, Ben Davidson (Liberal party of New York State), Jacques Torzyner (president of ZOA), and Professor Robert Hirshfeld discussing whether "Mayor Lindsay and Governor Rockerfeller were right to snub King Faisal", 7/18/66; R (Item 318, Item (/))
  - Same as Tape 318, R (Item 319, Item (/))
  - Same as Tape 319, R (Item 320, Item (/))
  - Interview by Haikal in Cairo, 1957; R (Item 321, Item (/))
  - Speech, Freedom Club, Los Angeles, California, 4/3/56; R (Item 322, Item (/))
  - Continuation of Tape 322, R (Item 323, Item (/))
  - Interview by Tom Reeky on "Background," ABC, Michigan, on AML's speech at the University of Michigan two days earlier; and excerpts of Shimon Peres who spoke a week earlier, R (Item 324, Item (/))
  - Colonel Mahmoud Younes, chairman of Suez Canal Authority, at luncheon of American-Arab Association, New York City, (introduced by General Wheeler), 1966; R (Item 325, Item (/))
  - Speech "The Road to Victory," Assuit University, Assuit, Egypt, 10/63; R (Item 326, Item (/))
  - a) Wooster College, Wooster, Ohio, 3/13/68; R (Item 327, Item (/))
  - b) Question and answer period
  - Speech, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 11/14/67; R (Item 328, Item (/))
  - Continuation of Tape 328 (question and answer period), R (Item 329, Item (/))
  - Speech, "Middle East: Friend or Foe?" City Auditorium, Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1/29/54; R (Item 330, Item (/))
  - Speech, "The Middle East: Another Vietnam?" State University of Washington, Pullman, Washington, 1/13/70; R (Item 331, Item (/))
  - arrival of John F. Dulles in Cairo, Egypt, 5/53; R (Item 332, Item (/))
  - Speech, "The Middle East: Another Vietnam?" University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 5/16/67; R (Item 333, Item (/))
  - Speech, "A Jew Demands Justice for the Arabs," and telephone tie-up to 15 cities, Islamic Center, Detroit, Michigan, 3/1/70; R (Item 334, Item (/))
  - Speech, "Where Goes the Middle East?" University of Colorado, Boulder, Colorado, 11/21/68; R (Item 335, Item (/))
  - Speech, "Where Goes the Middle East?" Hamilton College, Clinton, New York, 2/10/55; R (Item 336, Item (/))
  - Interview by Ezzidin Sirag, Libyan Broadcasting Service, Tripoli, Libya, on Palestine Day, 5/15/73; R (Item 337, Item (/))
  - Interview on Radio Cairo [questions in French - AML's answers in English], R (Item 338, Item (/))
  - Morning Chapell Call Requiem, "Poposal for a New Middle East Prophecy," Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, 2/13/68; R (Item 339, Item (/))
  - Speech, "Where Goes the Middle East?" Women's Society of Scarsdale, Community Baptist Church, Scarsdale, New York, 4/14/69; R (Item 340, Item (/))
  - Miscellaneous dictation, including on Saul Bellow (after '67), R (Item 341, Item (/))
  - answer to CBS editorial on U.S. Middle East policy, New York City, 12/2/74; R (Item 342, Item (/))
  - Miscellaneous dictatation, R (Item 343, Item (/))
  - Radio announcement of AML's speech "The Middle East Crisis: What Should America's Role Be?" at California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo, California, 4/27/76; R (Item 344, Item (/))
  - Miscellaneous dictation, including open letter to Mohammed Ali (Cassius Clay), c., April 1977; R (Item 345, Item (/))
  - Speech, "Where Goes the Middle East?" American Graduate School of International Management (Thunderbird), Glendale, Arizona, 3/26/79; C (Item 346, Item (/))
  - Speech and question and answer period, UNO group, Tokyo, Japan, 11/7/91; C (Item 347, Item (/))
  - a) Question and answer period Kywa Kyokai, Diet Building, Tokyo, Japan, 11/7/91; C (Item 348, Item (/))
  - a) Press conference, National Press Club, Washington, D.C., 6/12/85; C (Item 349, Item (/))
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1945-1984 (Photo file)
  2,313 prints, 37 negatives, 146 negative strips, 13 contact sheets, and 13 slides depicting Lilienthal and others in the United States and in various countries of the Middle East.